<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jiayang Zhang | Sheffield AI Research Engineering</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/jiayang-zhang/</link><atom:link href="https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/jiayang-zhang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Jiayang Zhang</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/jiayang-zhang/avatar_hu2a24c772eb1d447a68a189c6ea97beaf_2761752_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Jiayang Zhang</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/jiayang-zhang/</link></image><item><title>Multimodal AI for Parkinson's Disease</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/parkinson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/parkinson/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>University of Sheffield Collaborating Faculties&lt;/strong>: Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN) and Faculty of Engineering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>: Our project is dedicated to the development of artificial intelligence tools for Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease, designed to elucidate the underlying mechanisms of the condition and predict its progression. This initiative integrates data from multiple modalities—including genetic data, biomarkers, environmental factors, and medical examinations—utilizing advanced AI methodologies such as contrastive learning, foundation models, and causal discovery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Motivation&lt;/strong>: The growing interest in applying artificial intelligence (AI) to tackle Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease reflects a comprehensive appreciation of the condition&amp;rsquo;s widespread impact, its escalating incidence, the existing gaps in our comprehension, and the extraordinary research opportunities afforded by current data repositories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the second most prevalent neurodegenerative disorder in the UK, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease presents a formidable public health challenge. Its widespread nature underlines the pressing demand for novel treatment and management strategies, positioning AI as an ideal candidate to drive forward innovative solutions. Globally, the frequency of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease is on the rise, affecting an ever-growing number of individuals either directly or putting them at a significant risk of developing the condition. This increasing trend accentuates the urgent necessity for interventions that are both scalable and efficacious, areas where AI technology shines with potential. Despite thorough research efforts, the core mechanisms behind Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease remain a mystery. Here, AI&amp;rsquo;s ability to sift through and analyze large, complex datasets could unlock new understanding, setting the stage for transformative developments in how we treat and prevent the disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.ukbiobank.ac.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UK Biobank&lt;/a>, with its comprehensive data, emerges as a pivotal resource for AI research. The extensive scope of this data lays a robust groundwork for the creation and refinement of AI models, fostering considerable progress in our grasp and handling of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s. Leveraging AI, researchers are not just shedding light on the elusive causes of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease but are also crafting predictive models that foresee the disease&amp;rsquo;s trajectory, pinpoint therapeutic targets, and ultimately, instill hope in the countless lives touched by this afflictive illness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus, the convergence of AI and Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease research heralds an exciting era in the battle against neurodegenerative diseases. It offers a beacon of hope for enhancing patient outcomes, marking a vital step forward in our journey towards understanding, managing, and eventually overcoming such conditions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AI Brain Imaging for Nerve Pain Detection (UKRI funded)</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/nerve-pain-detection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/nerve-pain-detection/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>University of Sheffield Collaborating Faculties&lt;/strong>: Faculty of Medicine, Dentistry and Health, Faculty of Engineering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>External Partners&lt;/strong>: University of Oxford, University of Dundee, AstraZeneca&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>: Neuropathic pain, arising from damage or disease impacting the nervous system, stands as a significant health concern. Our project aims to develop an AI-based neuroimaging model capable of predicting treatment responses and clinical phenotypes in patients afflicted with neuropathic pain. We plan to conduct extensive external validation studies across multiple sites and conditions to ensure the development of a robust and objective AI-based neuroimaging model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Motivation&lt;/strong>: Chronic neuropathic pain afflicts one in ten adults over 30, stemming from injuries to the sensory nervous system. The incidence of this debilitating pain is anticipated to escalate due to ageing, a surge in diabetes cases, and improved cancer survival rates. Neuropathic pain markedly impairs daily functioning, manifesting symptoms like burning or &amp;rsquo;electric-shock&amp;rsquo; sensations, potentially leading to depression and a significant diminution in quality of life. Present medications provide only marginal relief to roughly half of the affected individuals, and are associated with side effects. Over the past quarter-century, the quest for more efficacious drugs for neuropathic pain has stagnated, a likely consequence of the diverse sub-types of the condition and the unpredictable nature of treatment responses. Collaborating with AstraZeneca and other universities, our endeavor is to unearth new biomarkers for neuropathic pain, aiming to invigorate drug development initiatives and enhance their effectiveness.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>