<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Donghwan Shin | Sheffield AI Research Engineering</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/donghwan-shin/</link><atom:link href="https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/donghwan-shin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Donghwan Shin</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/donghwan-shin/avatar_hub85bb59e2f02b928d35f39a215478f8e_6556_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Donghwan Shin</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/donghwan-shin/</link></image><item><title>Multi-fidelity Fusion and Optimization Theory and Applications</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/multifidelity-fusion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/multifidelity-fusion/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>University of Sheffield Collaborating Faculties&lt;/strong>: Faculty of Science, Faculty of Engineering and AMRC&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>: Our project aims to investigate novel methods to leverage a special type of multimodal data—multi-fidelity data—to improve AI model accuracy and efficiency, leading to scalable solutions in computationally intensive optimisation problems in various engineering disciplines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Motivation&lt;/strong>: Our goal is to create innovative techniques and toolsets capable of assimilating and being able to use multi-fidelity data effectively (i.e., providing the same outputs of high-fidelity datasets using lower-fidelity datasets), such as simulation outcomes from both coarse and dense meshes, and signals from high-cost precision sensors and low-cost basic sensors. We aim to enhance AI model accuracy without relying on highly accurate data obtained from high-cost precision sensors only, whilst improving efficiency metrics such as training time and memory cost. We will implement the proposed method in simulation-based testing for autonomous driving systems (ADS) to demonstrate the capability for the safety and reliability of self-driving cars with low-cost computation.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>