<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Sheffield AI Research Engineering</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/media/icon_hu885f0cfeed998fbf7dc869c80f754bbd_18100_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>Multimodal AI for Cardiothoracic Disease Diagnosis and Prognosis</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/multimodal_ai_for_cardiothoracic_disease_diagnosis_and_prognosis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/multimodal_ai_for_cardiothoracic_disease_diagnosis_and_prognosis/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>University of Sheffield Collaborating Faculties&lt;/strong>: Faculty of Medicine, Dentistry and Health, Faculty of Social Science, and Faculty of Engineering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>External Partner&lt;/strong>: Sheffield Teaching Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>: Our project aims to develop a sophisticated Artificial Intelligence (AI) system which can process multimodal, multi-vendor, multi-centre, and multi-pathophysiological cardiothoracic data, such as Chest Radiographs (CXR), Echocardiogram (ECG), Computed Tomography (CT), Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) and Electronic Health Record (EHR), to segment and classify pathophysiological features and improve the diagnosis, prognosis, and therapeutic response prediction of Cardiothoracic Disease (CTD) such as Pulmonary Hypertension (PH), Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) and Abnormal Heart Rhythms (AHR) to a level at which advanced methods such as contrastive learning, foundation model, meta-learning, few-shot and zero-shot learning can successfully extract interpretable clinical parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Motivation&lt;/strong>: Cardiothoracic disease refers to a variety of conditions that affect the heart and lungs, including coronary artery disease, heart failure, lung cancer, and diseases of the chest wall. These illnesses can impact the overall function and structure of the heart and lungs, and they often require specialised care, potentially including surgery. Despite substantial progress in medical technology, the early diagnosis of these diseases remains a challenge due to the complexity of disease development and the vague symptoms produced in the early stages. In our initial study, we will utilize the MIMIC datasets, which comprise various data modalities within a comprehensive open-access database. This dataset has been the foundation for high-quality research in areas ranging from intensive care and mortality prediction to disease classification in pathology. Additionally, we will use the in-house dataset, ASPIRE, provided by our collaborator, which also offers multiple data modalities, to further test our model. In the short term, the project&amp;rsquo;s success could lead to improved diagnosis and monitoring of CTD, potentially reducing the need for invasive procedures and facilitating personalised treatment plans. In the long term, our AI system could be adapted to more cardiovascular and respiratory diseases, revolutionising the approach to cardiothoracic medicine and benefiting countless patients worldwide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OCR Text Correction for Text Mining of Historical Documents</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/ocr_text_correction_for_text_mining_of_historical_documents/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/ocr_text_correction_for_text_mining_of_historical_documents/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;b>Overview&lt;/b>: This project addresses the critical issue of correcting noisily OCR&amp;rsquo;d historical documents, focusing on the British Library Newspapers (BLN) collection. BLN is a major corpus of over 200 years of scanned British newspapers from over 240 newspapers with textual data, visual data, and metadata available. Scanned newspaper images have undergone OCR (optical character recognition) processing, resulting in inaccurate transcriptions due to the degradation of the original documents. The project aims to employ advanced deep-learning techniques to improve the quality of these transcriptions. The final outputs will be high-quality corrected transcriptions of BLN and open-source code for OCR text correction, both of which would serve as valuable resources for humanities researchers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>Motivation&lt;/b>: Since the early 2000s, significant digitisation efforts have been undertaken to preserve and make accessible historical primary sources such as newspapers, early printed books, and handwritten documents. While these efforts have been instrumental in advancing humanities research, the low quality of OCR transcriptions remains a significant barrier to discovering new historical insights. The successful completion of this project promises both short-term and long-term benefits. In the short term, it will significantly enhance the transcription quality of BLN, enabling accurate and efficient searching within the collection as well as unlocking the potential for text mining, which was previously impractical due to low transcription quality. In the long term, the project&amp;rsquo;s success could revolutionise research on other large collections of historical documents, allowing researchers to track content changes, language evolution, and shifts in thought across different time periods. By being language-independent, the impact could extend to historical documents worldwide, advancing research on a global scale.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AI brain imaging technology to help revolutionise healthcare research for patients with chronic nerve pain (UKRI funded)</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/ai_brain_imaging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/ai_brain_imaging/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;b>Overview&lt;/b>: Neuropathic pain, arising from damage or disease impacting the nervous system, stands as a significant health concern. Our project aims to develop an AI-based MR neuroimaging model capable of predicting treatment responses and clinical phenotypes in patients afflicted with neuropathic pain. We plan to conduct extensive external validation studies across multiple sites and conditions to ensure the development of a robust and objective AI-based MR neuroimaging model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>Motivation&lt;/b>: Chronic neuropathic pain (NeuP) afflicts one in ten adults over 30, stemming from injuries to the sensory nervous system. The incidence of this debilitating pain is anticipated to escalate due to ageing, a surge in diabetes cases, and improved cancer survival rates. NeuP markedly impairs daily functioning, manifesting symptoms like burning or &amp;rsquo;electric-shock&amp;rsquo; sensations, potentially leading to depression and a significant diminution in quality of life. Present medications provide only marginal relief to roughly half of the affected individuals, and are associated with side effects. Over the past quarter-century, the quest for more efficacious drugs for NeuP has stagnated, a likely consequence of the diverse sub-types of the condition and the unpredictable nature of treatment responses. Collaborating with AstraZeneca, our endeavor is to unearth new biomarkers for NeuP, aiming to invigorate drug development initiatives and enhance their effectiveness.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>