<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prasun Chandra Tripathi | Sheffield AI Research Engineering</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/prasun-chandra-tripathi/</link><atom:link href="https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/prasun-chandra-tripathi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Prasun Chandra Tripathi</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/prasun-chandra-tripathi/avatar_hu7390dd96046e02f62aa26326ddcd85f4_162063_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.JPEG</url><title>Prasun Chandra Tripathi</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/prasun-chandra-tripathi/</link></image><item><title>AI brain imaging technology to help revolutionise healthcare research for patients with chronic nerve pain (UKRI funded)</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/ai_brain_imaging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/ai_brain_imaging/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;b>Overview&lt;/b>: This project aims to create a reliable and objective biomarker for neuropathic pain through the integration of artificial intelligence (AI) and magnetic resonance (MR) neuroimaging. In partnership with the globally renowned PAINSTORM Advanced Pain Discovery Platform, funded by the UK government (MRC, ESRC, and BBSRC), we possess a special chance to externally validate our method. This validation will utilise one of the most extensive prospective studies with meticulously categorised patients suffering from neuropathic pain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;b>Motivation&lt;/b>: Chronic nerve pain, or neuropathic pain (NeuP), affects one in ten adults over 30 due to injuries to the sensory nervous system. The prevalence of this pain is expected to rise due to ageing, increasing diabetes cases, and better cancer survival rates. NeuP significantly disrupts daily life, causing symptoms like burning or &amp;rsquo;electric-shock&amp;rsquo; sensations, and can lead to depression and severe reduction in quality of life. Current medications offer only limited relief to about half of the patients and come with side effects. The last 25 years have not seen much advancement in more effective drugs for NeuP, possibly because of the varied sub-types of the pain and unpredictability of treatment responses. The variability often results in unsuccessful drug trials. In collaboration with AstraZeneca, we aim to find new biomarkers for NeuP to boost the effectiveness of drug development initiatives.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>