<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jim Wild | Sheffield AI Research Engineering</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/jim-wild/</link><atom:link href="https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/jim-wild/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Jim Wild</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/jim-wild/avatar_hu5288420fb3731596d60a50ccec51a438_7880_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Jim Wild</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/jim-wild/</link></image><item><title>AI Brain Imaging for Nerve Pain Detection (UKRI funded)</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/nerve-pain-detection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/nerve-pain-detection/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>University of Sheffield Collaborating Faculties&lt;/strong>: Faculty of Medicine, Dentistry and Health, Faculty of Engineering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>External Partners&lt;/strong>: University of Oxford, University of Dundee, AstraZeneca&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>: Neuropathic pain, arising from damage or disease impacting the nervous system, stands as a significant health concern. Our project aims to develop an AI-based neuroimaging model capable of predicting treatment responses and clinical phenotypes in patients afflicted with neuropathic pain. We plan to conduct extensive external validation studies across multiple sites and conditions to ensure the development of a robust and objective AI-based neuroimaging model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Motivation&lt;/strong>: Chronic neuropathic pain afflicts one in ten adults over 30, stemming from injuries to the sensory nervous system. The incidence of this debilitating pain is anticipated to escalate due to ageing, a surge in diabetes cases, and improved cancer survival rates. Neuropathic pain markedly impairs daily functioning, manifesting symptoms like burning or &amp;rsquo;electric-shock&amp;rsquo; sensations, potentially leading to depression and a significant diminution in quality of life. Present medications provide only marginal relief to roughly half of the affected individuals, and are associated with side effects. Over the past quarter-century, the quest for more efficacious drugs for neuropathic pain has stagnated, a likely consequence of the diverse sub-types of the condition and the unpredictable nature of treatment responses. Collaborating with AstraZeneca and other universities, our endeavor is to unearth new biomarkers for neuropathic pain, aiming to invigorate drug development initiatives and enhance their effectiveness.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>