<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Xianyuan Liu | Sheffield AI Research Engineering</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/xianyuan-liu/</link><atom:link href="https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/xianyuan-liu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Xianyuan Liu</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/xianyuan-liu/avatar_hu42e6bb4f77b4f8df2d26e0165d9cae14_23239_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url><title>Xianyuan Liu</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/author/xianyuan-liu/</link></image><item><title>Digital Materials Discovery</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/digital-materials-discovery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/digital-materials-discovery/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>University of Sheffield Collaborating Faculties&lt;/strong>: Faculty of Engineering, Royce Institute&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>:
This project uses AI to accelerate the discovery of new materials crucial for green technologies. It explores both data and modelling aspects to predict material composition and properties, through two case studies: permanent magnetic materials and novel corrosion-resistant coatings.
The project uses machine learning algorithms for predictions, drawing on both existing and self-generated databases enriched by natural language processing. It addresses inherent challenges like data scarcity and imbalance through data augmentation and the integration of machine learning with physics-based models.
The project will deliver high-quality methodologies, open-source code, and a user-friendly interface to broaden the application of these predictive capabilities.
This has the potential to revolutionize materials discovery by enabling the software to autonomously predict material properties from specified compositions, paving the way for significant breakthroughs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Motivation&lt;/strong>:
The demand for sustainable technologies requires the discovery of novel materials with superior properties.
Traditional methods for materials discovery are time-consuming and resource-intensive due to their reliance on physical experiments and iterative testing, limited by both practical laboratory setups and human imagination.
This project bridges this gap by harnessing the power of AI, using machine learning algorithms, digital databases, and computational tools. This significantly reduces the time it takes to translate a concept into a material with desired properties.
By enabling autonomous prediction of material properties, this project has the potential to revolutionize the field of materials science. In the short term, it can accelerate the discovery cycle, leading to faster development of solar cells and energy-efficient materials. In the long term, this project could pave the way for entirely new materials with unforeseen properties, ultimately propelling advancements across diverse fields like aerospace, medicine, and electronics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multimodal AI for Parkinson's Disease</title><link>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/parkinson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shef-AIRE.github.io/project/parkinson/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>University of Sheffield Collaborating Faculties&lt;/strong>: Sheffield Institute for Translational Neuroscience (SITraN) and Faculty of Engineering&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>: Our project is dedicated to the development of artificial intelligence tools for Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease, designed to elucidate the underlying mechanisms of the condition and predict its progression. This initiative integrates data from multiple modalities—including genetic data, biomarkers, environmental factors, and medical examinations—utilizing advanced AI methodologies such as contrastive learning, foundation models, and causal discovery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Motivation&lt;/strong>: The growing interest in applying artificial intelligence (AI) to tackle Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease reflects a comprehensive appreciation of the condition&amp;rsquo;s widespread impact, its escalating incidence, the existing gaps in our comprehension, and the extraordinary research opportunities afforded by current data repositories.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As the second most prevalent neurodegenerative disorder in the UK, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease presents a formidable public health challenge. Its widespread nature underlines the pressing demand for novel treatment and management strategies, positioning AI as an ideal candidate to drive forward innovative solutions. Globally, the frequency of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease is on the rise, affecting an ever-growing number of individuals either directly or putting them at a significant risk of developing the condition. This increasing trend accentuates the urgent necessity for interventions that are both scalable and efficacious, areas where AI technology shines with potential. Despite thorough research efforts, the core mechanisms behind Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease remain a mystery. Here, AI&amp;rsquo;s ability to sift through and analyze large, complex datasets could unlock new understanding, setting the stage for transformative developments in how we treat and prevent the disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.ukbiobank.ac.uk/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">UK Biobank&lt;/a>, with its comprehensive data, emerges as a pivotal resource for AI research. The extensive scope of this data lays a robust groundwork for the creation and refinement of AI models, fostering considerable progress in our grasp and handling of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s. Leveraging AI, researchers are not just shedding light on the elusive causes of Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease but are also crafting predictive models that foresee the disease&amp;rsquo;s trajectory, pinpoint therapeutic targets, and ultimately, instill hope in the countless lives touched by this afflictive illness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thus, the convergence of AI and Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s Disease research heralds an exciting era in the battle against neurodegenerative diseases. It offers a beacon of hope for enhancing patient outcomes, marking a vital step forward in our journey towards understanding, managing, and eventually overcoming such conditions.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>